ADAM KIM

CYBERSECURITY PROFESSIONAL

Dependable IT professional with over 5 years in various areas of tech, seeking to tackle and resolve complex security challenges. Ascertained a well-rounded knowledge in network, cybersecurity, helpdesk, and programming to increase availability and productivity. Sharp client communication and leadership delivering outstanding outcomes to the stake holders. Seeking an entry level Cybersecurity Analyst position in your company where these skill sets can be applied and further developed as we excel together.

Akim456@gmail.com

AtomKim.com

**** 347-554-3119

in linkedin.com/in/adamkim456/

Resv

Skills

CYBERSECURITY

Data, Log, Packet Capture Analysis SIEM Tools

NIDS / NIPS / HIDS / HIPS

Incident Response Life Cycle

DNS / DHCP / Active Directory

Firewalls - WAF / VM / Network / Host

WAP Configuration / Management / Security

Data Encryption

Virtualization Type1 / Type2

Systems Hardening

Data Backup / Recovery / Secure Destruction NIST / PCI / HIPAA Compliance

NETWORK

Network Infrastructure Design

Network / Wireless / Cloud Security

Network Access Control (NAC / PNAC)

WAP / Router / Switch Configuration

DHCP / Static / Subnetting

Firewall / Port Forwarding

End Point / VoIP / CCTV Management

SOFTWARE

Windows & Mac OS

Linux Ubuntu & Kali

VMware

Wireshark / Packet Tracer / Zenmap

Itarian & Komodo

OBS / NDI / SRT / Nginx

HARDWARE

Building & Configuring PCs/Macs Routers / Switches / Peripherals

SOHO / Dell Sonic Wall

A/V Telepresence Systems

Device Audit

Stress Testing

PROGRAMMING

Bash Scripting

Java (Web Full Stack, Android)

HTML5 / CSS / BOOTSTRAP

SQL

BATCH / DOS

AHK

AGILE / SDLC / SCRUM

Employment

The Law Offices of Kim & Associates

Network Engineer / Cybersecurity GRC

Queens, NY Jan. 2019 - July 2021

Development and maintenance of network infrastructure, prioritized network availability and security for all employees within the company. Produced and preserved network & security policies to protect sensitive company and client data. Pioneered and implemented updated quarterly training on acceptable use policy. Strengthened company security posture by securing backups, air-gapping servers, and isolating subnets. Mitigated and responded accordingly to any external and internal threats. Built and hardened all new and older machines. Collaborated directly with the DFS to develop cybersecurity polices in accordance to 23 NYCRR Part 500(e). Published, tested, & documented thorough contingency plans for disaster recovery/Business continuity.

NETWORK

- · Redesigned physical and logical design of network infrastructure
- · Modeled and administered user access and group policies, subnetting, and static IP assignments
- Restructured 2 private internal NAS's and external cloud role based access (RBA) & connectivity
- · Strengthened wireless access points for secured allocation to employees and limited access to visitors
- Centralized end points to monitor malware, unauthorized apps, and system updates

CYBERSECURITY

- · Routine analysis of malicious files & rogue devices
- Performed audits to document devices, IP & MAC addresses, and physical ports.
- · Approved BYOD upon inspection and analysis
- Orchestrated & instructed acceptable use policy and security practice trainings
- Authored the 23 CRR-NY-500(e) Cybersecurity policy to completion, approved by the Department of Financial Services

HELP DESK

- Assembled 25+ desktop PCs, provided troubleshooting support, and responsible for equipment budgeting
- Converted 25+ office & 25+ personal PCs overnight for remote access for day 1 of the pandemic shutdown
- Forged imaged/clone master copies to reduce redeployment times of compromised machines
- Streamlined configurations for 20+ VoIP/analog phones, 5 printers, CCTV, and other peripherals
- · Developed scripts to automate day to day tasks for employees and increased productivity and office morale
- Designed & deployed telepresence systems for 5 conference rooms for court proceedings due to pandemic

HSBC Tri-state
IT/AV Specialist Oct. 2017 - June 2018

Team lead on multiple A/V projects for HSBC NYC Headquarters and neighboring branches across the tri-state. Accountable for A/V engineering for international conferences of up to 50 participants at one time, room surveys for Cisco telepresence system integrations, logistics, deploying, configuring, and decommissioning of systems.

Law Office of Kwangsoo Kim

Queens, NY Jan. 2015 - Mar. 2017

Personal Injury Protection (PIP) Admin

Expert in NY & NJ PIP / No-Fault procedures. Responsible for over 450 cases in various stages of litigation on the Supreme and Civil Court calendar in all 5 boroughs. Maintained persistent client relations, office administration, legal support for IME, EBT, 50H, and discovery/response.

Certifications

Education

B A Media Studies

CySA+ Cybersecurity Analyst CompTIA Certification (ETA 10/2021)	Per Scholas, Bronx NY Cybersecurity Analyst	2021
Cybersecurity Essentials Cisco Certificate	Per Scholas, Bronx NY Java Developer	2018
Networking Essentials	Queens College, Queens NY	2015

Cisco Certificate

Linux Essentials

Cisco/NDG Certificate

Notary Public

U.S. Department of State (#01Kl6420786)